Guide to the Leland Anderson family papers, 1880-2010 MS 916
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Leland Anderson family papers
1880-2010
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Anderson, Leland
MS 916
8 Linear Feet 7 boxes
The collection has a majority of photographs, newspaper articles, letters, and portraits.
Biographical / Historical
W. Leland Anderson served as one of the first Directors of the Texas Medical Center and as vice-president of Anderson, Clayton and Company. The collection includes family portraits, photographs, news article clippings, and family letters. The collection includes a number of Julia Anderson Frankel's photo albums and scrapbooks. Julia Anderson Frankel is considered a Houston community leader in which she has served as board member and trustee.
Scope and Contents
The collection has a majority of photographs, newspaper articles, letters, and portraits. Most of the photographs are of W. Leland Anderson and his family including albums of Julia Anderson Frankels. The other photographs are of W. Leland Anderson's late family from the 1800s - early 1900s. The collection also includes a photo album of Julia Anderson Frankel's husband, Russell M. Frankel.
Box 7 has a few class and family photographs with no specified dates.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Related Materials
William Lockhart Clayton papers, 1897-1966, MS 007, Woodson Research Center, Fondren Library, Rice University
Index Terms
Subjects
Cotton; Cotton; Agriculture
Document Types
photographs; clippings (information artifacts); family papers
- Series I: Photographs and scrapbooks
  - Clayton-Anderson family photographs, circa 1880-1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mr. & Mrs. W. Leland Anderson (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Julia Anderson Frankel, circa 1940-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Julia Anderson Frankel Baby Milestone Book, circa 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Julia Anderson Frankel Birthday, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Assembly Ball, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Spring Dance, Circa 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Julia Anderson Frankel, Circa 1960-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Julia Anderson Frankel- Birthday Party, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Russell M. Frankel- Childhood Photo Album, circa 1940-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Family and Class Photographs, circa 1910-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Julia Scott Anderson Baby Album, circa 1947-1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Julia Anderson Frankel Scrapbook, circa 1960-1970 (Box 2)
  - Julia Anderson Frankel Scrapbook, circa 1978-1993 (Box 3)
  - Julia Anderson Frankel Scrapbook, circa 1994-1999 (Box 4)
  - Julia Anderson Frankel Scrapbook, circa 2003-2008 (Box 5)
  - Russell M. Frankel Baby Album, circa 1947-1951 (Box 6)
  - Family Portraits (Box 7)